<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Phil in the Blank</title>
        <link>/tags/</link>
        <description>Latest blog posts from Phil in the Blank</description>

        
        <language>en-us</language>
        

        

        

        

        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        

        
        <atom:link href="/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        

        
            
        <item>
          <title>Dad and America</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/07/dad-and-america/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/07/dad-and-america/</guid>
          <description>My dad texted me “happy July 4th” the day of, and it prompted me to think about what it means to be an American.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>The Beliefs We Harbor</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/07/the-beliefs-we-harbor/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/07/the-beliefs-we-harbor/</guid>
          <description>What follows is something that happened in 2017. I wrote about it then for my friends and figure it’s worth reposting here, especially given the current state of affairs on the homefront and in the world.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Remember What You&#39;re Fighting For</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/06/remember_what_you_re_fighting_for/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/06/remember_what_you_re_fighting_for/</guid>
          <description>Had a lovely conversation with a woman named Natalie via DialUp, an app that aims to revive the magic and intimacy of phone conversations.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>On Attention and Cleaning One&#39;s Ears</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/04/on-attention-and-cleaning-ones-ears/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/04/on-attention-and-cleaning-ones-ears/</guid>
          <description>For the past few weeks I noticed some pressure and discomfort on the inside of my right ear upon waking. I didn’t give it much thought and dismissed it as a minor annoyance, but then I realized that the volume on my computer had been gradually raised over the last few weeks, likely to compensate for an increased lack of hearing.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Weekly</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/03/weekly/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/03/weekly/</guid>
          <description>I started the week in partial limbo. This usually happens when I lack a sense of direction and things to do.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Graduate School</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/02/graduate-school/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/02/graduate-school/</guid>
          <description>It’s been a long process of deliberation, but I’ve decided to attend graduate school at UVM.
It wasn’t an easy decision.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Change</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/02/change/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/02/change/</guid>
          <description>Change, by definition, is uncomfortable. It asks us to work against the quicksand of comfort, it forces us to relinquish the wornout marks we still wear, it beckons us to surrender to the tumultuous winds of the unknown.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Superpowers</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/02/superpowers/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/02/superpowers/</guid>
          <description>A dear friend and I send each other long voice messages when we want to update each other on our lives.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Emma</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/02/emma/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/02/emma/</guid>
          <description>In the airport, a young child from China sitting across me is working on a puzzle.
I watch as she pieces the parts together, then realize she’s missing the last one.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>To Hold</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/02/to-hold/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/02/to-hold/</guid>
          <description>More and more I find myself holding the pain of others. It’s a privileged place to be, to serve as the anchor that people hang onto when the currents of life become too tumultuous to bear, to guide through that necessary journey of self-annihilation before any growth may take place.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Intensity</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/01/intensity/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/01/intensity/</guid>
          <description>Between every relationship we ever had, have, and will have, there exists a unique configuration of constellations that defines its being.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Moments</title>
          <link>/blog/2020/01/moments/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2020/01/moments/</guid>
          <description>This is Alyona (and I).
We began writing letters to each other over a year ago toward the end of 2018.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Devotion</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/12/devotion/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/12/devotion/</guid>
          <description>It’s the day I’m supposed to be camping in Joshua Tree, but I find myself driving up the coast instead, hunting for answers.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Loneliness</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/12/loneliness/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/12/loneliness/</guid>
          <description>This essay is adopted from one I wrote awhile ago for a science and writing class.
All the lonely peopleWhere do they all come from?</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>An Ode to Young Adulthood</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/12/an-ode-to-young-adulthood/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/12/an-ode-to-young-adulthood/</guid>
          <description>There’s this drawing of a banana. Toward the stem it is fresh, premature, and budding with potential; toward the other end it is weathered and well-defined, filled with the hard-earned sweetness and history that a full life bestows.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Fall 2019</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/12/fall-2019/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/12/fall-2019/</guid>
          <description>I’m finally finished with the semester. Soon I’ll be heading home to see my parents, camp in Joshua Tree National Park, and soak in the California sunshine.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>A Recent Trip</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/08/a-recent-trip/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/08/a-recent-trip/</guid>
          <description>This past Sunday, I tried magic mushrooms for the first time. It wasn’t much – around a gram or so, which is a bit less than what this paper suggests for someone of my body weight – but it was enough to dig up some insights about myself and the nature of the mind.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Rome</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/06/rome/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/06/rome/</guid>
          <description>I recently went to Rome, and it was nothing short of stimulating, sensuous, and overwhelming. From the minimal use of ingredients in Italian cuisine to the incredible works of Michaelangelo and other Roman artists, everywhere you went, everything you touched, tasted and smelled, everything you experienced, it all seemed like some part of a grand plan aimed at steering one’s senses toward a deeper appreciation and understanding of beauty and aesthetics.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Bearing Witness</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/06/bearing-witness/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/06/bearing-witness/</guid>
          <description>There are 16 of us nestled in the sunlit alcove of the church. I look at the stranger sitting on a navy-blue cushion before me and wonder what she is thinking about.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>The Pale Blue Dot</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/03/the-pale-blue-dot/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/03/the-pale-blue-dot/</guid>
          <description>Propelled into space in 1977, NASA’s scientific objective of launching the Voyager I was to photograph the planets of the outer solar system.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Shoreless Seeds and Stardust</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/03/shoreless-seeds-and-stardust/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/03/shoreless-seeds-and-stardust/</guid>
          <description>I ventured out onto the lake today, this time beyond the frozen crest that marks the boundary between bay and lake, contemplating the last line of Maria Popova’s Figuring:</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Mary Oliver</title>
          <link>/blog/2019/01/mary-oliver/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2019/01/mary-oliver/</guid>
          <description>We met in the biting winter nights of my service year in New Hampshire. I listened with full attention as she illuminated the nuances of a world I thought I knew with the written word, hers, words that continue to remind me I am never truly alone, words that continue to show me the world is always at offer to the playground of my imagination.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Letters to a Young Scientist</title>
          <link>/blog/2018/08/letters-to-a-young-scientist/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2018/08/letters-to-a-young-scientist/</guid>
          <description>Veteran biologist and teacher of science Edward Wilson lays out a few principles for the young scientist to keep in mind as he/she/they proceed in their career:</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Serendipity</title>
          <link>/blog/2018/01/serendipity/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2018/01/serendipity/</guid>
          <description>We sift through life without any compasses to guide us through the messy unknown, like aimless treasure hunters searching for diamonds in the dark.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Forgiveness</title>
          <link>/blog/2018/01/forgiveness/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2018/01/forgiveness/</guid>
          <description>Forgiveness moves us toward a better future by inviting us to look at the past, at the unrelenting, painful ghosts that continue to permeate and darken each of our lives.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Feelings</title>
          <link>/blog/2018/01/feelings/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2018/01/feelings/</guid>
          <description>Feelings are fleeting by nature, like the passage of clouds on a warm summer day.
Though too often we wear them like immutable masks and declare, “This is me.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>18: Home</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/18-home/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/18-home/</guid>
          <description>After Belgium I spent a night in Prague and took a bus to Hungary the next morning. I stayed in Budapest for 10 days with Eszter, the Hungarian I had a crush on at the beginning of this whole adventure.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>17: The Final Goodbye</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/17-the-final-goodbye/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/17-the-final-goodbye/</guid>
          <description>I arrive in Belgium late in the afternoon. The weather is exceptional: half-clouded skies with no reservation of sunlight, a perfect balance of cool and warm.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>16: Santiago</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/16-santiago/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/16-santiago/</guid>
          <description>“How we spend our days is, of course, how we spend our lives.” –Annie Dillard
October 8, 2017 - Day 31 Pedrouzo, Spain.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>15: Letters Worth Czeching Out</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/15-letters-worth-czeching-out/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/15-letters-worth-czeching-out/</guid>
          <description>I wrote these letters to my friend, Stepan, from the Czech Republic. Including them because they might help to create a better picture of my experience.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>14: Letters to a Camino Soulmate</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/14-letters-to-a-camino-soulmate/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/14-letters-to-a-camino-soulmate/</guid>
          <description>These are the emails Marieke and I wrote to each other after she was gone. They might give you a better picture of my Camino experience.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>13: The Iron Cross</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/13-the-iron-cross/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/13-the-iron-cross/</guid>
          <description>October 1st, 2017 - Day 25 Dawn. A ridge of silhouettes and gray clouds against the dark expanse. A string of headlamps clambering up a mountain.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>12: Journal Entries from Day 22 - 24</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/12-journal-entries-from-day-22-24/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/12-journal-entries-from-day-22-24/</guid>
          <description>September 28, 2017 - Day 22 To be yourself–Easy to say, hard to do.What we think is not ours.What we believe is shaped by others.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>11: A Sea of Stars</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/11-a-sea-of-stars/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/11-a-sea-of-stars/</guid>
          <description>Day 21 4:30am. I inch out from my sleeping bag like a slug, careful not to disturb the others in the room, pack my things and head downstairs.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>10: Journal Entries from Day 17 - 20</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/10-journal-entries-from-day-17-20/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/10-journal-entries-from-day-17-20/</guid>
          <description>September 23, 2017 - Day 17 We are always on the cusp of collapse and redemption. Do we choose to rise, or do we settle and fall?</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>9: An Ode to the Road</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/9-an-ode-to-the-road/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/9-an-ode-to-the-road/</guid>
          <description>Each and every day I wake and walk with the sun.It starts low, climbing over hillsides, rising slowly.At last it finds its place in the skyand begins to color the Meseta.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>8: Gone</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/8-gone/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/8-gone/</guid>
          <description>I’ve sunken into the depths of an all-too-familiar melancholy.
She is gone. I am alone. My emotions swing to the erratic cadence of an unforgiving metronome.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>7: Goodbye</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/7-goodbye/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/7-goodbye/</guid>
          <description>Day 15. We’re sitting amid a small cluster of dining tables in the main plaza of Burgos, sipping on wine and eating tapas.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>6: Sunsets and Soulmates</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/6-sunsets-and-soulmates/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/6-sunsets-and-soulmates/</guid>
          <description>“Phil! I have a genius idea. You’re really going to like it.”
It’s the 12th day. Marieke, Stepan (a walker from The Czech Republic we met a few days ago), and I go to the top of a hill to catch the sunset.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>5: The Cusp of Time and Infinity</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/5-the-cusp-of-time-and-infinity/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/5-the-cusp-of-time-and-infinity/</guid>
          <description>In the morning we walk to Pamplona, our first city. I run into Maria and chat with her for a brief moment before running off with the girls to get breakfast.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>4: Möge die Straße</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/4-m%C3%B6ge-die-stra%C3%9Fe/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/4-m%C3%B6ge-die-stra%C3%9Fe/</guid>
          <description>Another gray and rainy day. We sleep in and start walking at 8am. After the deep and enlightening conversations of yesterday, we decide to walk in solitude –– together but left to the vicinity of our inner worlds.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>3: Tea</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/3-tea/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/3-tea/</guid>
          <description>Through the window I see
Sun-bathed flowers and untouched rock,
Blades of grass and untrodden walks,
Endless possibility.
I ask of you Time</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>2: First Ascent</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/2-first-ascent/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/2-first-ascent/</guid>
          <description>I wake to the sound of creaking bunk beds, rustling backpacks, and hushed chatter. 5:30 a.m. Time to go. I put my boots on, pack my sleeping bag, and head downstairs.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>1: Beginnings</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/1-beginnings/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/1-beginnings/</guid>
          <description>The Camino de Santiago is a network of pilgrimage routes that ultimately converge on the city of Santiago de Compostela in Northwestern Spain, where the great Saint James is rumored to be buried.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>0: Introduction</title>
          <link>/blog/2017/12/0-introduction/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>/blog/2017/12/0-introduction/</guid>
          <description>In May of 2017, while working in a Title I Elementary school in New Hampshire, I read a little fable called “Rebirth” by Kaval Ravikant.</description>
        </item>
            
        
    </channel>
</rss>
